Harsh Darji

harshdarji82@gmail.com | 519-702-3060

GitHub | LinkedIn

Five years of experience as an IT professional focused to obtain a challenging position in an organization that gives me an opportunity for self-improvement and leadership while contributing to the growth of the organization with my technical, innovative, and logical skills.

EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer

06/2021 - Present

Jewels By Love, France (Remote)

PHP – 90%, XML – 80%, JavaScript – 90%, Jira – 95%, E-commerce concepts – 90%, API – 80%

- Address and resolve technical issues in Magento stores, ensuring minimal downtime and optimal performance
- Develop and customize Magento extensions using PHP, XML, PHTML and JavaScript to enhance store functionality
- Creating server-side script that directly run via CMD for bulk operations and managed data integration with phpMyAdmin (MySQL)
- Applied concepts like inheritance, polymorphism and encapsulation and followed MVVM and MVC design patterns to ensure scalable and maintainable code architecture
- Conduct daily virtual meetings to discuss progress, challenges, and plans for the day
- Contributed to the issue tracking, sprint planning, backlog prioritization and reporting Using Jira

Associate Web Developer

09/2020 - 04/2021

Brainvire, India

SQL - 95%, MVVM - 95%, MVC - 90%, Monday.com - 80%, GitHub - 90%

- Develop clean and efficient code based on the requirements using various technologies like PHP, Magento, KnockoutJS, MVC, XML, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, SQL Server, etc. Integrate and deploy programs and websites. Troubleshoot, debug and upgrade the existing software.
- Designed, developed, and maintained Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD).
- · Contributed to automation, timelines, dashboards, customizable workflows and collaboration using Monday.com
- Responsible for creating new and updating existing extensions.
- Used version control system Git and platform GitHub for code collaboration, issue tracking and version management.
- Worked closely with designers, product managers, and other stakeholders to understand project requirements and deliver high-quality solutions.

Web Developer 07/2018 – 06/2020

Akash Technolabs, India

FileZilla - 80%, Slack - 70%, Workbench - 60%

- Developed a web-based application using PHP technologies like Laravel, MVC, SQL server, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS.
- Also responsible for unit testing, enhancement, and FTP deployment of the application.
- Use slack channels for different project or topics and integrate with other Agile tools for seamless updates.
- · Used project management tool Jira to track progress and collaborate with team members.
- Conducted performance tuning and refactoring of code to improve load times and resource utilization.
- Managed database using SQL (MySQL, MySQL Workbench, PostgreSQL).

EDUCATION

Mobile Application Development | GPA -3.9

09/2022 - 12/2023

Fanshawe College, London, ON

Bachelor of Computer Science & Information Technology

07/2015 - 06/2018

Gujarat University, India

PROJECTS

Virtual Cook | 🔘 | React Native, Material UI, Expo, React-redux, Expo-speech, Expo-sharing, React Native Paper, VS Code

• Utilized the React Redux structure/methodology for efficient state management. Integrated stack navigation and text-to-

speech using expo libraries.

- **Developed interactive features** like notification and phone shake and **utilized modal** to display recipe filter and sorting options, enabling users to **switch between language options**, French and English
- Additional features include recipe sharing, search options, dietary restrictions, app color customization, and access to random recipes.

Product On Rent | PHP, Laravel, jQuery, Ajax, MVC, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, MySQL, Bootstrap, PHP Mailer, Postman, VS Code

- Developed a web application for rental products using Laravel, adhering to MVC, MVVM, and MVBC structures.
- Managed database operations with MySQL Server and implemented server-side logic using PHP.
- Implemented pop-up messages using JavaScript and SweetAlert.
- Integrated PHP Mailer to send confirmation emails and utilized Ajax for dynamic country, state, and city selection functionality.

ASK ME For Immigration | PHP Core, PHP, MySQL, PHP Mailer, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap, jQuery, Ajax, JavaScript

- Designed to assist international students with immigration queries, providing information on universities/colleges, fees, contacting academic advisors, application procedures, and more.
- Implemented features for students like send follow request(s) to experts, post like, questions, answer and replies, similar to Instagram and Facebook functionalities.
- Developed interactive features such as notifications, likes, follow requests using jQuery, Ajax, and JavaScript.
- Utilized Bootstrap and custom CSS for an intuitive and user-friendly interface.

- Designed to showcase subcategories with category banners on the product listing page.
- Utilized MVVM pattern by overriding XML files.
- Created a new category attribute to display custom data, managed via InstallData and UpgradeData scripts.
- Created Block and Helper class to implement custom functionality.

SKILLS

Programming Languages:

Web Frameworks:

Database:

Concept:

•

Tools:

PHP, Java, JavaScript, XML, Swift, Kotlin, HTML5, CSS, C#, Node.js.

React Native, Magento, Laravel, WordPress, jQuery, MVC, MVVM, KnockoutJS. MySQL, MySQL Workbench, SQL Lite, SQL, Firebase, Relational Database. Agile, Scrum, IaaS, PaaS, SaaS, RESTful API, PWA, UI/UX, GIT, Excel VBA, Ajax,

Email Management, Microsoft Office.

Visual Studio Code, NetBeans, Jira, Postman, Docker, Xcode, Android Studio.

SOFT SKILLS

- Programming Languages
- Self-Starter
- Multitasking

- Code Structure & Architecture
- Problem Solving
- Teamwork

- Front-end & Back-end web development
- Organizational Skill